SIMEON P. HENDRICKS

www.linkedin.com/in/simeonhendricks • github.com/zeuselijah • (470) 869-4629 • Simeonhendricks@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 10+ years of experience in operations and project management. Solution-driven, lean and six-sigma focused, team building and detail-oriented, to lead teams to solve client pain points. Proven to develop strong relationships across cultures and teams to provide leadership in a fast-paced environment.

COMPETENCIES & SKILLS

Certified Scrum Master Agile Methodologies Project Management Six Sigma Green Belt

HTML, CSS, & JavaScript MongoDB, Express, Python and Django Strategic Planning

React and Node

Product Inspection Procedures Development Stakeholder Relations Quality Assurance

EXPERIENCE

Firefighter | Atlanta Fire Rescue Department, Atlanta GA

Sept. 2018 – August 2022

- Collaborated across teams to deploy Hazardous Crisis Management for Acts of God and human error to protect the safety and well being of life and property.
- Developed and implemented high intensity fire, EMT training for teams of 12+ increasing safety standards by 5% year over year.
- Implement inspections, audits and quality insurance, internally and with stakeholders to ensure that physical infrastructures meet city and state code and regulations.

Service Manager | Massey Services Inc | Atlanta GA

March 2018 – Sept. 2018

- Orchestrated 90% efficiency of production flow for a multi-million dollar service center that serviced a customer base of over 200 miles.
- Mobilized a team of 20 service technicians responsible for ensuring customer satisfaction and world class quality.
- Managed short and obtainable projects through Lean Methodologies to improve service technicians productivity by 10% month over month.
- Owned an annual budget of \$400,000, ensuring no oversights or mismanagement of funds through budget analysis and routine audits.

Locomotive Service Manager | CSX Transportation | Buffalo NY

Jan 2013 – July 2017

- Managed a team of 60 mechanical employees, providing trainings for and oversight of freight car and locomotive operations.
- Coordinated and maintained all business operations for Buffalo Service Center and Line of Road operations.
- Managed the handling, and maintenance of hazardous and safety protocols and procedures, including but not limited to Federal Railroad Administration guidelines, Environmental Protection Agency policies and SOPs/SOGs of CSX Transportation.

PROJECTS

Doctor's Portal General Assembly Immersive

October 2022

• A full-stack application utilizing the Python-based Django Web Framework for an interactive portal for doctor's.

Travel XP.Log | General Assembly Immersive
 A full-stack application utilizing MongoDB, Express, React, Node, vanilla CSS, Heroku, and Netlify for a full user interface experience.

Cattle Caller | General Assembly Immersive

September 2022

 A full-stack application utilizing Node, Express, MongoDB, CSS, Bootstrap and Heroku with functionality of full CRUD.

Let's-Get-Quote-ie!!! | General Assembly Immersive

August 2022

• A web-app utilizing HTML, CSS and JavaScript that renders random quotes and pictures.

EDUCATION

General Assembly Software Engineering Immersive, Remote October 2022

Software Engineering Fellow

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Chapel-Hill, NC 2017

Kenan-Flagler Business School CSK Transportation Emerging Leader

North Carolina A&T State University, Greensboro, NC

December 2012

Master of Science, Agricultural Education Completed: 18 credits

North Carolina A&T State University, Greensboro, NC Bachelor of Science, Industrial Systems Engineering Certification: Waste Management

Certifications:

September 2022 **Scrum Alliance**

December 2011

Certified ScrumMaster® (CSM®)